<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hydrology on Hung Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://ntthung.github.io/tags/hydrology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hydrology on Hung Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ntthung.github.io/tags/hydrology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why the 2022 Po River Drought Is the Worst in the Past Two Centuries
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/montanari2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/montanari2023/</guid>
      <description>The causes of recent hydrological droughts and their future evolution under a changing climate are still poorly understood. Banking on a 216-year river flow time series at the Po River outlet, we show that the 2022 hydrological drought is the worst event (30% lower than the second worst, with a six-century return period), part of an increasing trend in severe drought occurrence. The decline in summer river flows (−4.14 cubic meters per second per year), which is more relevant than the precipitation decline, is attributed to a combination of changes in the precipitation regime, resulting in a decline of snow fraction (−0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Multi-Year Drought Risk with the Transition Probability Matrix
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/henley2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/henley2023/</guid>
      <description>Manuscript under consideration with Water Resources Research.
More soon as we hear from the reviewers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncertain Benefits of Using Remotely Sensed Evapotranspiration for Streamflow Estimation-Insights from a Randomized, Large-Sample Experiment
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2022preprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2022preprint/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
