<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>archaeology on Hung Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://ntthung.github.io/tags/archaeology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in archaeology on Hung Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ntthung.github.io/tags/archaeology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-High Resolution Paleostreamflow for Southeast Asia: Proxy/Model Comparison
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/p4-seaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/p4-seaq/</guid>
      <description>This project aims to develop high-resolution data sets of proxy-derived and model-derived paleostreamflow for Southeast Asia.
We have submitted a proposal to the NSF P4CLIMATE program and results are pending.
More soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RADIATR: **R**econstructing **A**griculture **D**ynamics by **I**ntegrating **A**rchaeology and **T**ree **R**ings
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/radiatr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/radiatr/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we aim to use stable isotope ratios (δ18O, δ13C, and δ15N) to reconstruct past climate and agriculture dynamics in Asia. We have submitted a proposal to the NSF DISES Program and results are pending.
We have also received USD 10,000 in seed funding from the Lamont-Doherty Climate Center.
More soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydroclimatic Variability on the Qinghai-Tibetan Plateau and Demographic Patterns
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/tibet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/tibet/</guid>
      <description>We propose new reconstructions of past temperatures and precipitations on the Tibetan Plateau. Combining our new reconstructions with existing records, we seek to explore the role of climate in driving past changes in demographic patterns.
We have submitted a proposal to the NSF HEGS Program and results are pending.
We have also received USD 2,500 from the Department of East Asian Languages and Culture, Columbia University, to develop the course A Climate History of the Tibetan Plateau.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
