<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tree rings on Hung Nguyen</title>
    <link>https://ntthung.github.io/tags/tree-rings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tree rings on Hung Nguyen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ntthung.github.io/tags/tree-rings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-High Resolution Paleostreamflow for Southeast Asia: Proxy/Model Comparison
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/p4-seaq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/p4-seaq/</guid>
      <description>This project is funded by the US National Science Foundation, grant AGS-2302668. It aims to develop high-resolution data sets of proxy-derived and model-derived paleostreamflow for Southeast Asia.
Stay tuned for more updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RADIATR: **R**econstructing **A**griculture **D**ynamics by **I**ntegrating **A**rchaeology and **T**ree **R**ings
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/radiatr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/radiatr/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we aim to use stable isotope ratios (δ18O, δ13C, and δ15N) to reconstruct past climate and agriculture dynamics in Asia. We have submitted a proposal to the NSF DISES Program and results are pending.
We have also received USD 10,000 in seed funding from the Lamont-Doherty Climate Center.
More soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydroclimatic Variability on the Qinghai-Tibetan Plateau and Demographic Patterns
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/tibet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/tibet/</guid>
      <description>We propose new reconstructions of past temperatures and precipitations on the Tibetan Plateau. Combining our new reconstructions with existing records, we seek to explore the role of climate in driving past changes in demographic patterns.
We have submitted a proposal to the NSF HEGS Program and results are pending.
We have also received USD 2,500 from the Department of East Asian Languages and Culture, Columbia University, to develop the course A Climate History of the Tibetan Plateau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Longleaf Tree-Ring Network: Reviewing and Expanding the Utility of *Pinus palustris* Mill. Dendrochronological Data
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/harley2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/harley2023/</guid>
      <description>Longleaf pines have not only long leaves, but also long lives. Thus they are excellent materials to build tree-ring time machines. Grant Hartley led a ginormous effort to review everything longleaf in this paper. I was lucky to contribute a teeny bit.
I also got to learn how such a big project is executed. In the old days this would have been a monograph by a gentleman scientist. Science is more inclusive now, and a diverse team of authors work on this project together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Drought Risks Over the Past Four Centuries Amidst Projected Flood Intensification in the Kabul River Basin (Afghanistan and Pakistan)—Evidence From Tree Rings</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/khan2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/khan2022/</guid>
      <description>The Kabul River is a transboundary river spanning eastern Afghanistan and northern Pakistan. It is an important tributary of the Indus, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest rivers with intensive water withdrawals for human use. With climate change, the Kabul River is projected to have more frequent and larger floods, but the projections are very uncertain. To have a better understanding of these future projections, we need to look at how the region&amp;rsquo;s climate has changed in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Droughts, Pluvials, and Wet Season Timing Across the Chao Phraya River Basin: A 254-Year Monthly Reconstruction From Tree Ring Widths and &amp;delta;&lt;sup&gt;18&lt;/sup&gt;O
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2022/</guid>
      <description>Long records of river discharge, reconstructed from tree rings, help us understand how rivers behaved in response to past climates, and place projected climate changes in a broader perspective. While this knowledge is valuable, streamflow reconstructions have rarely been used to directly inform water management models, because tree rings are annual while water system models require streamflow data of higher resolutions, such as monthly or weekly. In our study, we use a rich network of tree ring data, consisting of both ring widths and stable oxygen isotope ratios, to reconstruct monthly river discharge at four key gauging stations that represent the four main tributaries of the Chao Phraya River, Thailand, thus bridging the gap between tree rings and water management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pakistan Hydroclimate over the past Five Centuries</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/pakistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/pakistan/</guid>
      <description>Summary The Kabul River is a transboundary river spanning eastern Afghanistan and northern Pakistan. It is an important tributary of the Indus, one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest rivers with intensive water withdrawals for human use. With climate change, the Kabul River is projected to have more frequent and larger floods, but the projections are very uncertain. To have a better understanding of these future projections, we need to look at how the region&amp;rsquo;s climate has changed in the past.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Proxy, Monthly Climate Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/project/thai-monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/project/thai-monthly/</guid>
      <description>Motivations &amp;amp; Objectives Tree rings, with annual resolution and precise dating, can provide temporally high-resolution proxy records of past climate. However, annually-resolved tree ring data still restrict how tree-ring-based paleoclimate reconstructions can be used in subsequent applications, where finer resolutions are desirable. For example, it is often difficult to compare annual climate reconstructions against historical events, because an event may have happened outside the target season of the reconstruction, or two opposite events (a flood and a drought) may be smoothed out by a reconstruction that targets the annual average (Wise, 2021).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi‐Proxy, Multi‐Season Streamflow Reconstruction with Mass Balance Adjustment
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2021/</guid>
      <description>Long history of river discharge, or streamflow, can be reconstructed from tree rings. These reconstructions help us understand the water cycle in the past, but they have not been widely used in water resources operations. This is because reconstructions are often annual (having only one data point per year). By combining different tree species and different features of tree rings (for example, ring width and stable isotope ratio), it is possible to reconstruct seasonal streamflow in addition to the annual one, and that is our first goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent Streamflow Variability in Monsoon Asia Over the Past Eight Centuries—Links to Oceanic Drivers
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2020/</guid>
      <description>Ten of the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest rivers are located entirely within the Asian Monsoon region. They provide water, energy, and food for 1.7 billion people. To manage these critical resources, we need a better understanding of river discharge—how does it change over a long time? Are there common variation patterns among rivers? To answer these questions, we use information derived from tree rings to reconstruct average annual river discharge history at 62 gauges in 16 Asian countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Value of ENSO State for Urban Water Supply System Operators: Opportunities, Trade-Offs, and Challenges
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/libisch2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/libisch2019/</guid>
      <description>The El Niño Southern Oscillation (ENSO) is a major driver of global hydro-climatic variability, with well-known effects on floods, droughts, and coupled human-natural systems. Its impact on urban settlements depends on both level of exposure and preparedness; two factors that are responsible for severe cuts on millions of people in developing countries, where urban water supply relies almost entirely on rainfall-dependent sources. To understand whether information on the ENSO state could help mitigate the effects of droughts, we use Metro Manila&amp;rsquo;s water supply system as exemplifying case study, for which we design “traditional” and adaptive management policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Linear Dynamical Systems Approach to Streamflow Reconstruction Reveals History of Regime Shifts in Northern Thailand
</title>
      <link>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ntthung.github.io/publication/nguyen2018/</guid>
      <description>Streamflow reconstruction involves estimating streamflow volumes in the distant past using statistical techniques and long range climate proxies. Conventionally, this is done using linear regression techniques which model streamflow as a linear function of climatic inputs. These models do not consider catchment dynamics, although in reality, streamflow volume depends on both climatic inputs and the state of the catchment (whether it is wet or dry). Here, we contribute a novel reconstruction technique, based on linear dynamical systems, that models explicitly the catchment state and its interaction with climatic inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
